Guide to the William Styron Papers, 1855-2019 and undated RL.01267
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material Series, 1963-1996
  - Audio materials, 1963-1996; 3
    - Wm. Styron, Ossie Davis, and Mike Wallace phone interview, from Wallace at Large, 8/1/68, 1968-08-01; 46
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0082)
    - Conversation between Th골se de St. Phalle and Styron, re: conference in Russia, 1969; 47
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0006)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0047)
    - Tape recording of panel discussion with Wm. Styron, subject: "Confessions of Nat Turner," Hartford, Conn., June 1969, 1969 June; 48
      - 1/4" open reel original (Box AV11, Audio-reel RL01267-RR-0002)
      - Compact disc preservation master (Box AV11, Audio-disc RL01267-CD-0002)
    - William Styron interviewed by Dr. Robert K. Morris, 1973; 49
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0001)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0002)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0003)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0004)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0005)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0042)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0043)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0044)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0045)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0046)
    - An unrehearsed interview with William Styron for the Robert Penn Warren Oral History Project. Interview conducted by Susan Allen in Roxbury, CT, 1980-05-05; 50
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0009)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0050)
    - Interview of Styron by Paul Baily for broadcast by BBC, 1982-08-02; 51
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0030)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0071)
    - Sophie's Choice read by Wolfram Kandinsky, part I, produced by Books on Tape, Inc., 1984, 52
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0010)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0011)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0012)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0013)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0014)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0015)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0016)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0017)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0018)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0019)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0020)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0021)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0022)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0023)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0024)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0025)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0026)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0027)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0028)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0029)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0051)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0052)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0053)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0054)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0055)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0056)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0057)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0058)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0059)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0060)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0061)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0062)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0063)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0064)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0065)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0066)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0067)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0068)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0069)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0070)
    - Interview of Styron by James L. W. West III on Thanksgiving 1986, Styron's home, Roxbury, CT, 1986-11-27; 53
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0031)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0032)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0033)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0072, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0072_01, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0072_02)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0073, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0073_01.wav, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0073_02.wav)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0074, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0074_01.wav)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0034)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0035)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0075)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0076)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0036)
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0037)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0077)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0078)
    - Duke University Club, 1992-10-27; 54
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0008)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0049, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0049_01.wav, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0049_02.wav)
    - Gray Matters: Depression and the Brain and A Conversation with Mike Wallace, Art Buchwald, and William Styron, The Dana Alliance for Brain Initiatives, 1996, 55
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0007)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0048, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0048_01.wav, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0048_02.wav)
    - Talk given by Styron at City Arts of San Francisco hosted Maya Angelou, undated; 56
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0038)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0079)
    - Chicago anti-Semite to W.S., undated; 57
      - Audiocassette original (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0039)
      - Audiocassette use copy (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL01267-CS-0080, Digital-materials RL01267-SET-0001, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0080_01.wav, Audio-file RL01267-CS-0080_02.wav)
- Scrapbooks, ca. 1925-1968
  Scrapbooks assembled by Styron's father documenting his son's life and later literary career. Scrapbook 1 begins with childhood photographs, artwork, and an analysis of young Styron's handwriting. The remainder of this volume and the 2 later volumes are filled primarily with reviews and publicity generated by Styron's first three novels, interspersed with occasional letters and photographs.
  - Scrapbook 1 ca. 1925-1968 (restoration) (Box SC 1)
  - Scrapbook 2, ca. 1939-1967 (Box SC 2)
  - Scrapbook 3, ca. 1959-1965 (Box SC 3)
  - Fragile - Original of scrapbook 1 (Box SC 4)
- Miscellaneous Material Series, 1855-1991 and undated
  Miscellaneous papers include literary awards and medals and accompanying documentation, genealogical information, an autograph/commonplace album of Catherine Clark (Styron's great-aunt), honorary degrees awarded to Styron, a guestbook (1979), and legal papers pertaining to the publication of Styron's works.
  - Awards and medals, 1970-1989, 8 items (Box M 1)
  - Catherine Clark's Album, 1855-1859 (Box M 2)
  - Guestbook from party celebrating Styron's 54th birthday and the publication of Sophie's Choice, 1979 (Box M 2)
  - Genealogical information (undated) (Box M 2)
  - Legal papers pertaining to Lie Down in Darkness, 1959-1964 (Box M 2)
  - Legal papers pertaining to Set This House on Fire, 1961-1962 (Box M 2)
  - Miscellaneous legal papers, 1951-1980 and undated (Box M 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1951-1991 and undated (Box M 2)
- Oversize Material, 1967-1993
  - Serials (Box OS 1)
    - 1967, Oct. 15-31 - La Quinzaine Littéraire "Styron et les Noirs," (p. 12) (Box OS 1)
    - 1979, July 30- Variety Advertisement for Sophie's Choice (Box OS 1)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box OS 1)
  - 1982 - Poster for "Sophie's Choice" (film) (Box OS 1)
  - 1993 - "Vanishing South" Calendar, featuring art of Hubert Shuptrine with commentary by Styron (Box OS 1)
  - 1979 - Book-of-the-Month Club advertisement for Sophie's Choice (Box OS 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1967-1989, 2 folders (Box OS 1)
  - Promotional poster for Sophie's Choice, English ed., circa 1980 (Box OS 2)
  - Commandeur de l'ordre des Arts et des Lettres: Award certificate and related correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box OS 2)
  - Primo Levi clipping and related memo, 1988 (Box OS 2)
  - Chance in a million, facsimilie keepsake proof, 1993 (Box OS 2)
  - Darkness Visible poster, mounted on foam board, undated (Box OS 2)
  - The Confessions of Nat Turner poster, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
- Accession (2006-0105), 1 box
  Unprocessed addition (06-105) (.4 lin. ft) contains Styron's copy of The Confessions of Nat Turner and a binder of letters from Styron to Bertha Krantz, Robert D. Loomis, and others, 1967-1993.
  - Styron memorial service materials (Folder 1)
- Accession (2007-0145), 2007, 1 folder
  Unprocessed addition (07-145) (6 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 2007) contains copies of material from Styron's memorial service, including the program, book of reminiscences, and transcript. This material is boxed in box 1 of 08-142.
  - Styron memorial service materials (Folder 1)
- Accession (2008-0012), 1943-2006 and undated, 2 boxes
  Unprocessed accession (0.8 lin. ft.; 600 items) which includes Styron's leather portfolio, handwritten drafts of his writings, typescripts, essays, speeches, and some correspondence from his to his father (dated 1943-1952). Also includes correspondence from his wife, Rose, around the time of his death in 2006, and a copy of the New York Times obituary. Also includes a leather portfolio with drafts of his work, photographs, clippings, and a photograph album from his daughter's film, Shadrach.
  - William Styron leather portfolio with drafts (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Drafts and essays (3 folders) (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Literary portraits (published and drafts) (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Speeches and writings (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Letters to his father, 1943-1952 (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Published articles and essays, some drafts (Box 1 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Drafts and published short stories, including the following: (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
    - Essays on Sophie's Choice (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
    - Lie Down in Darkness (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Drafts, essays, and short stories relating to war (5 folders) (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Correspondence from Rose, 2006 (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Photographs, clippings, photograph album, 1992-1998 and undated (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
  - William Styron interview transcripts, 2006 (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
  - Obituary, 2006 (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
- Accession (2008-0072), 1990-2003 and undated, 1 box
  Unprocessed addition (08-072) (180 items, .6 lin. ft.; dated 1990-2003 and undated) comprises mainly letters to Styron regarding his works, especially DARKNESS VISIBLE. Also includes letters regarding appearances requested or planned.
  - unspecified (Box 1 (Acc. 08/072))
- Accession (2008-0142), 1966-2003 and undated, 2 boxes
  Unprocessed addition (08-142) (388 items, .8 lin. ft; dated 1966-2007 and undated) mainly comprises incoming correspondence, which occasionally contains clippings, photographs, and other incidental materials. In addition, includes original manuscripts for several short works by the author, many annotated, as well as some handwritten manuscript pages for SOPHIE'S CHOICE. There are also two dvds of Styron's memorial service. Box 1 of this material includes Acc. 07-145.
  - unspecified (Box 1 (Acc. 08/142))
  - Correspondence, 1979-1991 and undated (9 folders) (Box 1 (Acc. 08/142))
  - Acc. 07-145 Memorial service program, reminiscences, and transcript (Box 1 (Acc. 08/142))
  - Memorial Service dvds (Box 1 (Acc. 08/142))
  - Manuscript originals: Sophie's Choice, Cannes Film Festival notes, "Shabaka", Virginia Foster Durr, Caleb (Box 1 (Acc. 08/142))
  - unspecified (Box 2 (Acc. 08/142))
  - Manuscript originals (5 folders): Yet alone shall I prevail, Saipan: July 1945, The way of the warrior (Box 2 (Acc. 08/142))
- Accession (2008-0294), 1 box
  Unprocessed addition (0.4 lin. ft.; 300 items) collected by James L.W. West III, a literature professor at Pennsylvania State University. A portion of this accession remains on deposit. Included are original and digitally scanned manuscripts, drafts, essays, short stories, and speeches. This accession is included in Box 2 (Acc. 08/012).
  - James West III addition (6 folders) (Box 2 (Acc. 08/012))
- Accession (2011-0142), 1 box
  Addition (11-142) (0.6 lin. ft.; 500 items) was donated by Styron's editor, Robert Loomis. It includes drafts and clippings, as well as photographs used in Styron publications.
  - Yet Alone Shall I Prevail draft, undated (Box 1)
  - A Tidewater Morning drafts, 1993 (Box 1)
  - The Way of the Warrior draft, 1985 and undated (Box 1)
  - Various essays, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Styron, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Photographs from publications (Box 1)
- Accession (2012-0017), 1 box
  - Cimarron Review 12 (July 1970), and note from William Swanson to Styron, 9 Oct. 1970 (Box 1)
    Issue includes "Religious Implications in The Confessions of Nat Turner" by Swanson (pp. 57-66)
  - Michael Stephens, Circles End, 1982, and note from Stephens to Styron, 28 Feb. 1982 (Box 1)
  - Carlos Fuentes, Aura, 1986 (Box 1)
    Inscribed to Styron; has Rose Styron's ownership signature
  - Hiber Conteris, Ten Percent of Life, uncorrected proof (1987), with note from Conteris to Styron, 26 July 1987 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Architectural Digest associate editor Adele Cygelman to Styron, 30 July 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ron Schick and Julia van Haaften, The View from Space: American Astronaut Photography, 1962-1972 (1988), with foreword by Styron (Box 1)
  - Neil Casey, ed., Unholy Ghost: Writers on Depression, 2002 (Box 1)
    Has Rose Styron's ownership signature, as well as her underlinings/notations (relevant to Styron) throughout introduction
- Accession (2012-0131), 2 boxes
  Proofs and galleys related to In the Clap Shack; manuscript fragments of The Way of the Warrior and a few essays; and a research and clippings file on Nat Turner.
  - Proofs of In the Clap Shack, undated (Box 1)
  - Proofs of In the Clap Shack, 1973 (Box 1)
    Master set, first pass
  - Proofs of In the Clap Shack, undated (Box 1)
    Master set, second pass
  - Foul matter, In the Clap Shack, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Manuscript fragments, The Way of the Warrior, undated (Box 1)
  - Essay manuscript fragments, undated (Box 1)
  - Research and clippings, The Confessions of Nat Turner, 1967-1971 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    Clipped reviews and articles about Styron's novel (some covering the backlash against it) and the film adaptation, as well as correspondence, notes, and research documents.
  - Manuscript fragments, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Typed manuscript, The Way of the Warrior, undated (Box 2)
  - Extra copy of onion paper copy, undated (Box 2)
- Accession (2013-0017), 1 box
  Original blocks used to create advertisements for William Styron's novel The Confessions of Nat Turner.
  - Set of two printing blocks (Box 1)
- Accession (2015-0030) and (2016-0025), 0.3 Linear Feet
  - Correspondence with Thomas P. Peyton and Peyton's family, 1944-2002 (Box 1)
    Contains 20 letters, clippings, and a photograph, primarily Styron's letters, dated 1944-2002, to friend and fellow marine,Thomas P. Peyton, and to Peyton's family members. Includes a few letters written between Peyton family members regarding Styron. Also contains newspaper clippings and one black-and-white photograph of Styron in military uniform in 1944.
  - Correspondence with Carl Mahakian, 1969-2007 (Box 1)
    Addition (16-025) comprises 27 items, mainly letters and notes from Styron to Carl Mahakian. There is also an autographed photograph, and three letters to Mahakian from Jim West, who requests help with his biography of Styron. In addition, there is an invitation to Mahakian to attend Styron's private memorial service and several published obituaries, along with a Spanish translation of Darkness Visible and a Book-of-the-Month Club flyer for The Confessions of Nat Turner. Material is dated 1969-2007.
- Accession (2016-0003), 1959-1983; 0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
  Archive of letters and postcards collected by Edmond Miller between his first meeting with Styron (5 May 1984) and the publication of Selected Letters of William Styron (4 Dec. 2012). Includes letters to Louis Auchincloss, Louis Untermeyer, George Core, Robie Macauley, Alan Abrams, Vearl Moody, and others. Also contains some published books and printed materials.
  - This Quiet Dust and Other Writings, by William Styron, including inlaid postcard addressed to Mr. Abrams, 1983 (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
  - The Confessions of Nat Turner, by William Styron, including an inlaid letter to Louis, 1967 (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1999; undated (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
  - Typescript copy of poem: A Collection of Hymns... (1754), undated (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
  - New York Times clipping about Styron's editorial, 1976 (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
  - "Nat Turner: The Final Reckoning of Things," by George Core (reprint), 1968 (Box Acc. 16/003: 1)
- Accession (2019-0014), 1990s; 0.1 Linear Feet
  35 mm slides donated by Joel Foreman.
  - Documentary slides, 1990s (Box Acc. 19/014: Box 1)